<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Rabbeinu Tam</string>
    <string name="Today">Today</string>
    <string name="specify">Specify Date</string>
    <string name="shabbat">Shabbat</string>
    <string name="shabbat_he">שבת</string>
    <string name="title_location_permission">No location permission</string>
    <string name="text_location_permission">
        Ideally, this app needs location permissions in order to accurately calculate the zmanim.
        Therefore, it is better to allow the app to see your location. We do not use your location
        for any other purpose than to calculate the zmanim. (Note: As of Android 11, the app can not
        ask you for location permissions more than once per install. You might need to re-install
        the app to use your location.) \n\n However, if you still do not want to give location
        permissions, you can choose to enter a zipcode and the app will try to find your location.
    </string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="setup_elevation">Setup Elevation</string>
    <string name="mishor_request">If you want to use Mishor (Sea Level) Sunset for your calculations
        of Rabbeinu Tam, just press the button below:</string>
    <string name="mishor_sea_level">Mishor (Sea Level)</string>
    <string name="manual_button">If you want to specify the elevation level (in meters) yourself,
        press this button:</string>
    <string name="manual">Manual</string>
    <string name="chaitables_request">If you want to get this information from chaitables.com,
        press this button:</string>
    <string name="chaitables">ChaiTables</string>
    <string name="long_explanation">Some opinions hold that the actual sunset that should be used
        for calculating zmanim is when sunset is seen at the highest point in the city.
        However, some do not hold of this opinion. Therefore, I left this part up to the user.
        Note that elevation does NOT affect degree based zmanim.</string>
    <string name="choose_date">Choose Date</string>
    <string name="specific_explanation">Press the button below to find out when Rabbeinu Tam is for
        a certain date:</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="how_the_calculations_work">How the calculations work</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about">About Activity</string>
    <string name="about_text">
        "Why I created this app.\n\n"

        "I created this app because I did not want to calculate manually when Rabbeinu Tam is"
        "every week. Since I learnt how to calculate Rabbeinu tam, I have been doing it in my head"
        "every week, however, I realized that I could just create an application to do the"
        "calculations for me, therefore, I set out to create this app.\n"
        "However, once I saw that I was doing all the work anyway, I decided to expand my app to"
        "include more opinions (shitot).\n\n"

        "What's the deal with elevation?.\n\n"

        "I added elevation input into this application because there are many opinions that hold"
        "that elevation should be included into the calculations. As obviously, the length of the"
        "day will be longer the higher the person is, since he is able to see the sun for a longer"
        "period of time. In Yerushalayim (Jerusalem), elevation makes sunrise and sunset around 7"
        "minutes earlier/later. However, not everyone takes this into account. Many opinions just"
        "calculate sunrise and sunset from sea level (Mishor).\n"
        "There are also opinions that use the degrees of the sun under or over the horizon. These"
        "opinions do not care about elevation of the person, rather where the sun is in the sky."
        "If you are using these opinions for your calculations, you can just choose the mishor"
        "(sea level) option and it will ignore elevation.\n"
        "Because of these many opinions, I just left the option to add elevation up to the user."
        "\n\n"

        "There is already a zmanim android app, why did you create another app?\n\n"

        "Two reasons: First of all, I wanted the practice of creating an android application."
        "Second of all, my app includes elevation in the calculations of Rabbeinu tam."
        "Whereas, other zmanim apps only include elevation for sunrise and sunset but NOT for the"
        "calculations of Rabbeinu tam and other opinions.\n\n"

        "Why did I get a pop up when I traveled to another place?\n\n"

        "Since elevation changes from city to city, and we need to find the highest visible place"
        "in the city for our calculations. I added a feature that checks the current name of the"
        "place you are located at, and the app checks every time you start the app whether you are"
        "in the same city. This feature is not perfect and it might be more annoying than helpful."
        "\nTherefore, you can choose to never get asked again about this issue."

    </string>
    <string name="calc_explanation_text">
        "Listed below are the details of how each opinion is calculated.\n\n"
        "All of the calculations use the KosherJava API.\n\n"
        "Please note that all the times are rounded up to the nearest minute. Whereas sunset is not"
        "rounded at all, rather the seconds are cut off.\n\n"
        "If you want an opinion added to the app, please feel free to contact me through the email"
        "button above.\n\n"

        "72 Zmaniyot Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 72 zmaniyot (seasonal/temporal) minutes, or 1/10th of the"
        "day after sunset (elevation included). This is the default selected opinion of the app"
        "when you first install the app. The Ohr HaChaim calendar in Israel uses this calculation,"
        "with elevation included, to calculate sof zman Rabbeinu Tam according to Rabbi Ovadiah"
        "Yosef ZT\"L. The actual times will be off by a minute or two or more from the calendar"
        "itself. Here are two reasons as to why the times might be off:"
        "1.) The calendar was written in an older programming language. 2.) The KosherJava API"
        "uses different algorithms to get sunrise/sunset, and including elevation also has multiple"
        "different algorithms to it as well. I have left everything to their default settings."
        "This is also the way that the Minchat Cohen in Ma'amar 2:4 calculates Rebbeinu Tam's time"
        "of tzait hacochavim, where each Mil, out of 4, is 18 minutes. The calculation takes the"
        "time between sunrise and sunset and divides it by 12 to get a zmaniyot hour, and then we"
        "take 1.2 of that hour and add it to sunset. Alternatively, you could take the amount of"
        "time between sunrise and sunset and divide it by 10, which will give you a 10th of the day"
        "(which is also 72 minutes), and add that to sunset.\n\n"

        "90 Zmaniyot Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 90 zmaniyot (seasonal/temporal) minutes, or 1/8th of the"
        "day after sunset (elevation included). This is where each Mil, out of 4, is 22.5"
        "minutes. The calculation takes the time between sunrise and sunset and divides"
        "it by 12 to get a zmaniyot hour, and then we take 1.5 of that hour and add it to sunset."
        "Alternatively, you could take the amount of time between sunrise and sunset and divide it"
        "by 8, which will give you an 8th of the day (which is also 90 minutes), and add that to"
        "sunset.\n\n"

        "96 Zmaniyot Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 96 zmaniyot (seasonal/temporal) minutes, or 1/7.5th of the"
        "day after sunset (elevation included). This is where each Mil, out of 4, is 24"
        "minutes. The calculation takes the time between sunrise and sunset and divides"
        "it by 12 to get a zmaniyot hour, and then we take 1.6 of that hour and add it to sunset."
        "Alternatively, you could take the amount of time between sunrise and sunset and divide it"
        "by 7.5, which will give you 7.5th of the day (which is also 96 minutes), and add that to"
        "sunset.\n\n"

        "120 Zmaniyot Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 120 zmaniyot (seasonal/temporal) minutes, or 1/6th of the"
        "day after sunset (elevation included). This is based on the opinion of the Magen Avraham"
        "that the time to walk the distance of a Mil according to the Rambam's opinion is 2/5 of an"
        "hour (24 minutes) for a total of 120 minutes based on the opinion of Ula. This is where"
        "each Mil, out of 5, is 24 minutes. The calculation takes the time between sunrise and"
        "sunset and divides it by 12 to get a zmaniyot hour, and then we take 2 of those hours and"
        "add it to sunset. Alternatively, you could take the amount of time between sunrise and"
        "sunset and divide it by 6, which will give you a 6th of the day (which is also 120"
        "minutes), and add that to sunset.\n\n"

        "50 Regular Minutes:\n\n"

        "This is the opinion of Rabbi Moshe Feinstein and should only be used in New York, USA."
        "This opinion is calculated as 50 regular minutes after sunset.\n\n"

        "60 Regular Minutes:\n\n"

        "This is the opinion of the Chavas Yair and the Divrei Malkiel."
        "This opinion is calculated as 60 regular minutes after sunset (elevation included)."
        "Where each Mil, out of 4, is 15 minutes.\n\n"

        "72 Regular Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 72 regular minutes after sunset (elevation included)."
        "This is according to the Machtzit Hashekel and the Pri Megadim. Where each Mil, out of 4,"
        "is 18 minutes.\n\n"

        "90 Regular Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 90 regular minutes after sunset (elevation included)."
        "This is according to the Magen Avraham according to the Rambam's opinion where each Mil is"
        "18 minutes and according to Ula who says that there are 5 Mil between sunset and Tzait."
        "\n\n"

        "96 Regular Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 96 regular minutes after sunset (elevation included)."
        "Where each Mil, out of 4, is 24 minutes.\n\n"

        "120 Regular Minutes:\n\n"

        "This opinion is calculated as 120 regular minutes after sunset (elevation included)."
        "This is according to the Magen Avraham according to the Rambam's opinion where each Mil is"
        "24 minutes, or 2/5th of an hour, and applies it to Ula who says that there are 5 Mil"
        "between sunset and Tzait.\n\n"

        "16.1 Degrees:\n\n"

        "This calculation is based on the same calculation of 72 minutes but uses a degree based"
        "calculation instead of 72 exact minutes."
        "This calculates the time of tzait at the point when the sun is 16.1° below the horizon."
        "This is the sun's dip below the horizon 72 minutes after sunset according Rabbeinu Tam's"
        "calculation of tzait around the equinox in Jerusalem.\n\n"

        "18 Degrees:\n\n"

        "This calculates the time of tzait at the point when the sun is 18° below the horizon.\n\n"

        "19.8 Degrees:\n\n"

        "This calculation is based on the same calculation of 90 minutes but uses a degree based"
        "calculation instead of 90 exact minutes."
        "This calculates the time of tzait at the point when the sun is 19.8° below the horizon."
        "This is the sun's dip below the horizon 90 minutes after sunset according Rabbeinu Tam's"
        "calculation of tzait around the equinox in Jerusalem.\n\n"

        "26 Degrees:\n\n"

        "This calculation is based on the same calculation of 120 minutes but uses a degree based"
        "calculation instead of 120 exact minutes."
        "This calculates the time of tzait at the point when the sun is 26° below the horizon."
        "This is the sun's dip below the horizon 120 minutes after sunset according Rabbeinu Tam's"
        "calculation of tzait around the equinox in Jerusalem.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="helper_text">Welcome to the Rabbeinu Tam App, this app was made to help you
        find out when sof zman rabbeinu tam is! There are three steps to setting up the app first.\n
        1.) Setup elevation for where you are currently located. In this first step is the setup
        screen that you should have first encountered when starting up the app. Some opinions hold
        that sunset is when you see the sun set at the highest point of the city. You can enter
        mishor, or you can enter the amount of elevation manually in meters, or if you don\'t know
        the amount for your area, you can find out that info through the chai tables website. Note
        that you do not need elevation for degree based calculations.\n
        2.) There are multiple opinions that you can choose from as the user of this app in the
        settings menu. If you want to know the details of that specific opinion and how the app
        calculates the times for rabbeinu tam, check out the "How the calculations work" menu
        option.\n
        3.) There are three screens to choose from in the main view of the app. The middle one is
        for when rabbeinu tam is for today. The left one is if you want to choose a specific day on
        the calendar for when rabbeinu tam is/was. Lastly, there is the right one that shows when
        rabbeinu tam is for this shabbat/shabbos. In addition to all of this, there is a feature
        that will tell you when to update the elevation if you leave the city that you currently
        set up the app for. The reason for this feature is because elevation will change bases on
        the city you are located in. You will have to update it every time you move around.
        However, this feature will only turn on if you use elevation.
    </string>

    <string name="opinion_header">Opinion (Shita)</string>
    <string name="contact_header">Contact the developer</string>
    <string name="opinion_title">Opinion to use</string>
    <string name="title_activity_calc_explanations">CalcExplanationActivity</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="zipcode">Zipcode</string>
    <string name="enter_a_zipcode">Enter A Zipcode</string>
    <string name="enter_your_zipcode">Press this button to enter your zipcode:</string>
    <string name="press_this_button_to_use_your_location">Press this button to use your location:</string>
    <string name="ask_for_location">Ask for location</string>
</resources>